<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Sysadmin | PugglePay]]></title>
  <link href="http://devblog.pugglepay.com/blog/categories/sysadmin/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://devblog.pugglepay.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-16T15:59:35+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://devblog.pugglepay.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[dev]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dev@pugglepay.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where is my stack? (Part 1): Goodbye Torquebox]]></title>
    <link href="http://devblog.pugglepay.com/blog/2013/10/09/where-is-my-stack-part-1-torquebox/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-09T13:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://devblog.pugglepay.com/blog/2013/10/09/where-is-my-stack-part-1-torquebox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So this is how it ends.</p>

<p>This week was the last week we ran TorqueBox in production. We've had
it running in production for 5 months. That's something! We
switched to TorqueBox in the first place to avoid headache with system
administration. Sadly, There Ain't No Such Thing As A Free Lunch
(TANSTAAFL), and we traded our problems with new ones, namely JRuby
and the JVM.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Previously on "PugglePay"</h2>

<p>In an <a href="/blog/2013/05/03/torquebox-or-how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-the-jvm/">earlier post</a>, I discussed some problem we had with TorqueBox from the very
beginning, but that we thought could overcome:</p>

<ul>
<li>slower tests</li>
<li>memory leaks</li>
<li>no zero-downtime deploy</li>
</ul>


<p>The only problem that was solved (and only recently) was the zero
downtime deploy. Other problems have appeared in the meantime:</p>

<ul>
<li>gem incompatibility</li>
<li>shaky OpenSSL support</li>
<li>very tricky setup with Spork</li>
<li>assets pre-compile that take forever</li>
</ul>


<h2>What to do?</h2>

<p>Most of those problems are related to JRuby, and I'm confident that
they will be solved someday. Another thing to point out is that we
migrated a fairly large application, so it might be easier to spot
memory leaks when building an app from the ground up.</p>

<p>But for our case, we reached the conclusion that TorqueBox was not a
good fit given our current needs, and went therefore the other way.</p>

<p>And that meant the Unix way.</p>

<p>Instead of adding the one big component, we've had to add a bunch of
smaller ones. We are now using Nginx+Passenger Enterprise as web-server,
Redis+Resque+resque_scheduler for cluster-wise scheduling, and Monit for
keeping all those services running.</p>

<p>So we did not want to become full-blown sysadmin, but that became the
only viable option for us.</p>

<p>We were only treating the symptom though, and not the decease: we did
not want to become Sysadmins because the tooling we've been using for
system administration were so painful to use.</p>

<p>So that's how it all began: with looking for a replacement for our
own mixture of ruby scripts and Chef recipes...</p>

<h2>On the next episode of PugglePay Development</h2>

<p>The team learns new encryption techniques ("We should totally use
GPG!"), discover new tools ("Ansible all the things!") and write some
libraries ("Mr. F~~").</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
